

VALTER CALDEIRA

LEAD DATA SCIENTIST

> ABOUT ME

Start working as a full-stack java developer for 3 years. In 2017, I become a Data Scientist and create a team from scratch in Novabase GTE.

I have been working as Data Scientist and Team Leader. Responsible for creating and developing ML solutions, providing technical solutions that ensure application performance, lifecycle agility, maintainability and governance.

I'm always learning new technologies and love to challenging myself every day.

CONTACT

- +351 926 055 290
- valterjpcaldeira@gmail.com www.valterjpcaldeira.github.io
- O Torres Vedras, Lisboa

INTERESTS









WORK EXPERIENCE

+ Beats Medical, Lisbon

2021 - Current

LEAD DATA SCIENTIST

Focus on Speech Therapy using multiple NLP techniques (One Patent Pending). Create an environment of RWD to be consumed by others. Implementation of TUG with only acceloremeters using multiple Al algorithms.

+ Tenthpin, Lisbon

2019 - 2021

LEAD DATA SCIENTIST

Several projects in healthcare: Article summarization and insights gathering for Research Company: Python (Keras, TensorFlow, Sklearn, Gensim, Nltk, etc.). Deployment of Invoice Classification for a drug company: Python (Pandas, Numpy, Sklearn, Tensorflow). Power BI dashboard and SAP ByDesign Reports Development

+ Novabase GTE, Lisbon

2017 - 2019

DATA SCIENTIST - TEAM LEADER

Several projects in government: Web Scraping project to gather insights about UK companies using NLP: Python (Selenium, MongoDB Atlas, Flask, Nginx, Sklearn, Gensim, Nltk.). Classify (CAE) activity code based on a description sentence (Portuguese Language): Python (Pandas, Numpy, Sklearn, Gensim). Using NLP algorithms to help ensure Quality control in Mozambique Census: Python (Pandas, Numpy, Levenshtein distance). POC for Transportation Company to count the number of persons inside a bus just using image: Python (OpenCV, Tensorflow, Angular, Websockets)

Novabase Portals, Lisbon
JAVA FULL STACK DEVELOPER

2014 - 2017

2020

> SKILLS

PYTHON

NLP

AZURE

ML/AI

POWER BI

SQL

EDUCATIONS & CERTIFICATES

+ Microsoft
MICROSOFT CERTIFIED: AZURE FUNDAMENTALS

+ Genova, Università degli Studi di Genova 2018
INTERNATIONAL SUMMER SCHOOL ON DEEP LEARNING

+ Lisbon, Instituto Superior de engenharia de Lisboa 2010-2014 SOFTWARE AND COMPUTER ENGINEERING DEGREE